(IF I HAD A HEART PLAYING)
-(ARROW WHOOSHING)
-(VASE SHATTERING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
KALF: That was impressive.
I modified
the Frankish weapon.
It has a much
greater range now.
The Franks will not expect
to be attacked
-by their own weapon.
-(LAGERTHA IN NATIVE TONGUE)
Freyr, we summon you.
(CHANTING)
We summon you.
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
With the blood
of this sacrifice,
now is the time.
ALL: Ahhh!
(WEAPONS CLINKING)
Bjorn must have
murdered our Berserker.
It's a pity.
It doesn't matter.
Really? How can you say so?
Because we have eyes
in Ragnar's household.
Anything we need
to know, we'll find out.
Bjorn's weakness.
Ragnar's weakness.
The time to strike.
-Through Torvi?
-Of course through Torvi.
Otherwise,
I'll kill her child.
She knows I'll do it, too!
(GRUNTS)
-(WEAPONS CLINKING)
-(GRUNTS)
WOMAN: (IN DISTANCE) Ahhh!
Lagertha must never
know what we did.
(STRUGGLING)
Who would tell her? Hmm?
What were you
two talking about?
Erlendur was telling me
how he has forgiven
Torvi for leaving him.
-Really?
-Hmm.
LAGERTHA: That young man
still surprises me sometimes.
I, too, have a surprise.
I am with child.
(CHUCKLES)
That makes me so very happy.
Me too.
More than I can say.
Although it is
still early days.
Marry me, Lagertha.
Marry me.
I have always known
that we were fated
to be together.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Lagertha?
-I'm sorry.
-Don't be sorry.
Don't ever be sorry.
Say that you'll marry me.
-(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
-(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Who is he?
(SIGHS) You heard.
He's a king.
From Tamdrup,
wherever that is.
And you trust him?
No!
I don't trust him either.
(THUDDING)
Why do you not care
for your daughter Siggy?
-MAN: Bring some more
of the shields.
-(BOAT CREAKING)
I care for her.
She just reminds me
of things I'd rather forget.
What kind of man
takes a mother
away from her child?
(ROPE THUDDING)
You tell me.
You tried to take me
away from my mother.
That is not the way it went.
If you remember,
your mother left me.
You left me.
It is not easy being a father.
It is even harder
being a husband.
Maybe I have failed at both.
No.
VIKING 1: I need a bit more
slack on the sail.
(WHISPERS) I have definitely
failed at being a husband.
-(CHUCKLES)
-VIKING 2: Need a hand?
VIKING 1: Take more than that.
VIKING 2: No, three will do.
-VIKING 1: Bring it here.
-Where do you think?
-HARALD: I want that
close to me.
-(PADDLES THUDDING)
VIKING 3: Why would we?
VIKING 1: Oil these oars!
How many boats and
men do you have?
WOMAN: More?
No, take more.
Take one more.
I will go get one.
Do you have enough?
Twenty boats.
About 600 men.
I told Ragnar
mine is a small kingdom
for now.
VIKING 1:
Better for the night.
And when will they arrive?
They must already
be on their way.
My brother Halfdan
is bringing them.
VIKING 3: Bring him on board.
Can you fill these?
Is your brother like you?
No.
He's much worse.
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING) He's much worse.
You have such ambitions.
What else is there?
What are we here for
except to achieve fame,
just like your father?
Isn't that what
you want too, Bjorn Lothbrok?
Be honest.
You don't know me.
And fame
won't make
your small kingdom any bigger.
SENTRY: Rider!
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: How many are there?
-(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
-(SWORDS CLINKING)
Open the gates!
ECBERT: Werferth.
We are met to decide
how to deal with Mercia.
Now, I am almost decided
that the only way now
is a full-scale invasion
of their kingdom.
And, yet, if there were some
other way of restoring Queen
Kwenthrith to her throne,
I think we must explore it.
Have you any more
idea of the identity of
the nobleman you knew as "W"?
Let me help you please, Sire.
The warring factions
of my kingdom
are always
known by the first letter
of their leader's name.
"W" stands for Wigstan.
He has royal blood,
as well as being one
of the most powerful
warlords in Mercia.
Yet he is obviously not
part of the Ruling Council.
No. Wigstan would
find it unbearable
to belong to any group.
His interests are
always personal.
Then you don't trust him?
Trust him?
(CHUCKLES) My Lord,
no one should
ever trust Wigstan!
So there is
no dealing with him?
Absolutely not!
The only way forward,
the only choice now,
is for both of you noble kings
to raise your armies
and invade Mercia
and rid my kingdom
of all the factions
who want to ruin me!
Me!
The only legitimate ruler
of that poor, ravaged,
raped and abused land.
(SIGHS) I agree
with the Queen.
There is no other choice now.
ECBERT: Huh.
So it seems.
Very well.
We shall take your advice.
(WHIP SNAPPING)
(MUTTERING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Wife,
come to bed.
I said...
No.
Why not?
I don't want to.
(EXHALES DEEPLY) Very well.
(VOICE CRACKING)
Then go sleep with my father,
(LOUDLY) you whore!
Yes, yes, and why don't
you go and sleep
with your mistress, the Queen.
Gives you another reason
to flagellate yourself!
-(GROANS)
-Go on. Hit me.
Hit me if it pleases
you, husband.
But it makes no difference,
either to you or me.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
You are husband to me
in name only,
as I am wife to you.
But you're otherwise free
to do as you will.
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFS)
(AETHELWULF EXHALING)
-(EXHALES)
-(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
We had an argument.
Aethelwulf?
He called me your whore,
which I am
and have freely chosen to be.
Do you want me to leave?
(HOWLING IN DISTANCE)
(PAPERS RUSTLING)
This was my wife's ring.
My wife died in childbirth.
I cannot tell
you the pain of it.
And I was resolved
never to marry again.
But I would like you
to wear it
if you will.
(BELL RINGING)
I cannot wait to take control
of my northern lands
and set up my own court.
You have some business
here first, remember?
Some family business.
ROLLO: I know.
A man can dream, can he not,
of dancing naked on the sand?
In any case,
my father needs you.
He needs a strong man
to support him
and to guide him.
(SIGHS) He has Count Odo.
I don't like Count Odo.
Nor do I trust him.
Of course,
it's possible that he could
die in the fighting.
Slain by some
unknown assailant.
And then the Emperor
would just have to
rely more on you.
Only a coward
(INHALES)
kills a man
by stabbing him in the back.
That is what
a Viking would say.
But you are no
longer a Viking.
In Frankia, we do
certain things differently.
That is something you'll
have to learn, my love.
(CHUCKLES) Something you'll
certainly have to learn.
(BELLS RINGING IN DISTANCE)
(MEN TALKING SOFTLY)
(DOORS CLOSING)
CHARLES: You asked
for a private audience.
Why?
Your Highness, forgive me,
I am reluctant to discuss
matters which relate
directly to my superior.
CHARLES: You mean Count Odo?
Then absolve
yourself of any guilt
and just say what
you have to say.
Highness, I am troubled
that you always
trust his word.
Why?
Should... Should I not
trust his word?
Because he is not
always worth believing.
Why, pray,
is he not worth believing?
Because he is ambitious.
Ambitious beyond ambitious.
So that even an Emperor's
crown would not sit
untidily upon his head.
(BIRDS SHRIEKING IN DISTANCE)
An Emperor's crown?
I cannot believe it!
What... What are you saying?
(SHOUTING) Do...
Do you have any proof of this?
I have the word
of his mistress.
And, as your Highness knows,
a man will always
divulge the truth
first to his mistress,
and only afterwards,
if at all,
to his wife.
Very well.
Let me talk to his mistress.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
CHARLES: For God's sake!
How should I
trust the evidence
of this woman?
Because this
woman is my sister.
CHARLES: Is it true?
THERESE: Yes, Your Highness.
And?
Does Count Odo talk
freely of his ambitions?
Yes, he does.
Very freely.
His ambition
(STUTTERING) to replace me?
To become
Emperor?
Yes, exactly.
His ambition
to become Emperor.
Then...
Then I beg you,
(STUTTERING) please,
stay close
to Count Odo.
Report to me
anything which might
signal his treachery.
Now, go! Leave me!
(SOBBING IN DISTANCE)
(CHUCKLES)
ODO: The forts have been
built according to your
instructions, Your Grace.
Eventually there will be
an iron chain
which can be raised
between them
to prevent the passage
of any boat upriver.
We should still place
some boats beyond
this barrier,
in case they break through.
Hopefully, they will be
unable to do so.
You don't know
my people like I do.
They don't recognize
any barriers,
except as obstacles
to be overcome.
What has become clear
to both the Emperor
and myself
is that, if we were
to lose Paris,
we would lose everything.
For then the enemy
would command
the Marne, the Seine
and the Yonne rivers,
and the country would lie open
as far as Rheims.
We must hold Paris
whatever the cost.
There is no alternative.
No other choice.
When my brother returns,
everything will be
decided here.
(BIRD CHITTERING)
(SIGHS)
(CHITTERING CONTINUES)
Is this how you looked?
Yes.
Though my hair
was much shorter.
What is the name
of your kingdom?
China.
And who rules it?
The Emperor Dezong,
of the Tang Dynasty.
I want to know
about your father.
My father was a... A merchant.
Well respected.
Rich enough to own a boat.
What about the Emperor?
Tell me about him.
The Emperor had
many daughters...
Mmm.
...with his wives
and concubines.
His concubines
were looked after
by the palace eunuchs.
Eunuchs?
Men who are not men.
Why are they not men?
Their manhood was cut off,
so they could not
have sex with the Emperor's
wives or slaves.
I don't like that.
No.
They didn't like it either.
(YIDU SNICKERS)
(CHUCKLES)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHISPERS) Are you one
of the Emperor's daughters?
(EXHALES)
-My father was a merchant.
-I know.
You told me that before.
I don't know you.
And you don't know me.
Yet I want to tell you
my most terrible secret.
-Do you want to hear it?
-Yes.
Mmm-hmm?
I can share your burden.
Mmm.
I am small,
but I have broad shoulders
and I am not afraid.
I will tell you
when you tell me the truth
about your father.
-(GRUNTS)
-(GASPS)
All right.
Then give me
more of that medicine.
(BIRD CHITTERING)
(CHOPPING)
-(HORN BLOWING)
-(CHATTERING)
Bjorn Ironside,
come and sit with me.
We should talk to one another.
You don't trust me.
I have no reason to trust you.
You have told me
of your ambitions.
Whether my ambitions
come true or not,
it's not up to me.
As well you know.
'Cause I can
make sure they don't.
(SNIFFS)
I will never give you
any cause to kill me.
(SCOFFS)
That is not for you to say.
I may find cause
where others may not.
Who knows?
(DRUM MUSIC STARTS PLAYING)
But for now anyway,
we are allies.
And we shall go
together to Paris.
And we shall fight together.
Is it not so?
You and Ragnar need
my warriors.
You need my ships.
I can't wait for Paris,
Bjorn Ironside.
I cannot wait.
We shall destroy
those Christian folk!
They have seen nothing yet.
We are the masters now!
-Is it not so?
-ALL MEN: Yes! Yeah!
-ALL MEN: Yes!
AELLE: So we are agreed,
we'll raise an army
and attack Mercia.
There is no alternative,
my Lord Aelle.
Not if we wish to see Queen
Kwenthrith placed once
more upon the throne.
(HORSES NEIGHING)
Travel safely, my Lord.
You are the best of allies.
AELLE: I'm a simple
man at heart,
-but full of conviction.
-ECBERT: Your convictions,
do you credit.
Farewell, my child.
Take heed
of what I've told you.
I will always
listen to you, Father.
But also to my own conscience,
and weigh such things in the
balance, as it pleases you.
It does not always please me.
But enough!
Women are frail.
Farewell, children.
Remember your duties,
say your prayers,
and banish the Devil
from your thoughts.
Such good advice,
my Lord Aelle.
Farewell.
KWENTHRITH: King Ecbert?
MAN: Front King's Guard!
-Yes, Queen Kwenthrith?
-MAN: All men forward!
MAN: Move out!
I need to know
that I can trust you.
That you will do
what you promised me.
Why would you doubt me?
You've heard me speak
plainly and in public.
I doubt you
for one reason only.
And that is that you and I are
somewhat alike.
Then do not judge
yourself too harshly.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR CREAK OPEN)
Lord,
you know me for a sinner.
My sins are
carnal, venal,
and unforgivable.
I know that.
And I think you have
already decided
to cast me out
into the darkness,
like a fallen angel,
to suffer in purgatory,
or the fires of hell,
for all eternity.
Think you, Lord,
that I can look upon such
scenes with equanimity?
That I do not dream,
in the dead of night,
of returning to your light
and the promises of heaven?
Am I not a man
like other men?
And yet,
I would sup with the Devil
if he would show me
how to achieve
my earthly goals.
Your kingdom, Lord,
as you have said,
is not of this world,
but my kingdom is.
And therefore,
there is no help for me.
No other way for me
but eternal damnation.
(GROANS)
(EPIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(HORNS BLOWING)
MAN 1: A boat's come in!
MAN 2: They're here!
MAN 3: Bring him in!
MAN 4: Over here!
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(CHEERING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
-Brother.
-Brother!
This is Kattegat!
This is Kattegat.
Come.
(KNIFE THUDS)
King Ragnar,
this is my brother Halfdan.
Meet the notorious
King Ragnar.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
HALFDAN: It's a great honor.
When do we sail for Paris?
LOTHBROK:
You seem eager to fight.
HALFDAN: Yes, it's true.
Not just
for the sake of fighting,
but for the beauty of it.
And against
the Christians, yes.
I hate the Christians.
In the name of Odin,
I would kill them all.
You'll have the opportunity
to kill a great number of them
once we reach Paris.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNIVES THUDDING)
-(CHEERING AND LAUGHING)
-WOMAN: Faster!
-Argh!
-(LAUGHING)
(DRUMS PLAYING)
(SHOUTING AND LAUGHING)
(SHOUTING AND
LAUGHING CONTINUES)
They'll be wondering
where you are.
I doubt it.
(SIGHS)
What are you thinking about?
Paris.
You must be excited
to be going back.
(SOFTLY) No.
I feel so old.
When I was young,
I had the passion to win,
but now, with age
and all that comes with it,
I have lost the desire.
And the strength.
A few years ago
I established a settlement
in a distant country
where I took many
of my people and friends
to make a new life
for themselves.
But shortly after
my departure,
they were all slaughtered.
Their homes
destroyed and burned.
I live with such guilt
because of it.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
And nobody knows.
My father's the Emperor.
(LAUGHS)
-(SHOUTING AND LAUGHING)
-(MUSIC CONTINUES)
They say he left Kattegat
a boy and came back a man.
Killed a bear
with his bare hands.
With his own hands?
Hmm.
(MUSIC STOPS)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Who is that?
It is Floki, the boat builder.
For some reason,
no one will tell me
he has fallen out
with King Ragnar.
Ask him.
HALFDAN: Floki.
Boat builder.
Sit down with us.
Yes, Floki. Sit down.
Make room.
Both of you join us.
-Fill the horns.
-Sup.
This is
my younger brother, Halfdan.
-He's keen to know you.
-All right.
So, you are the genius
that built the boats
that changed our world,
and helped made Ragnar
so famous!
Why would he fall out
with someone like you?
Because I killed
his pet Christian.
-Floki!
-(CHUCKLES)
Skol.
To new friendships.
Skol!
(SOFTLY) Skol.
(EXHALES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
(SHUDDERS)
(MOANS SOFTLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MOANS)
(EXHALES SOFTLY)
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
(MOANS)
(KNIFE SLASHING)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
-My turn!
-Here, catch it!
(GIGGLING)
Mine!
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
Ivar, do you want to play?
CHILD: Got it!
CHILD: It's mine,
give it back!
Now you go!
CHILD: Here! To me!
Throw it!
Here!
Give it here!
-Not to him.
-CHILD: No, you...
Higher!
My turn!
To me!
Come on! Here!
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Do not be afraid.
It's not your fault.
(WHISPERS)
Everything is all right.
Everything will be all right.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
What is that?
Can I see?
Where did you find this?
I took it from someone.
Why are you so interested?
I want to talk to you.
What about?
Us.
We have moments
when I feel so close to you,
especially when
you're inside me, but then
you don't want to talk,
and I wonder why
you really came for me
and took me away
from my child.
(CHUCKLES)
Torvi.
I talk to you.
By the way,
that was Erlendur's ring.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
He got it from his father,
King Horik.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
You look... Lagertha,
you look so beautiful.
This is always how I imagined
this moment.
Wherever I am,
I don't ever want to forget
how you looked on
our wedding day.
(GASPS)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Earl Kalf is dead.
WOMAN: Long live Earl Ingstad!
ALL WOMEN: (CHANTING)
Long live Earl Ingstad!
MAN AND WOMEN:
CROWD: Long live Earl Ingstad!
Long live Earl Ingstad!